Guide to the Silberling Financial Reports, 1919-1942 JL021
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Silberling Financial Reports,
1919-1942
JL021
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
1.5 Linear feet
Silberling, Norman J., 1892-1944
Biography
Norman John Silberling, a faculty member at the Stanford University Graduate School of Business (1935-1944), published weekly reports on the economy. In 1929 he organized Silberling Research Corporation, Ltd., which concentrated on financial counseling and forecasting.
1892 Year of birth
1914 Graduated with A.B. from Harvard
1915 Received A.M. from Harvard
1919 Received Ph.D. from Harvard
1920 Instructor of Economics at Harvard
1920-1921 Assistant Professor of Economics at Dartmouth
1922-1929 Associate Professor of Economics at University of California
1926 May Begins Publishing the weekly Silberling Reports
1929-1930 Professor of Economics at University of California
Late 1929 Starts Silberling Research Corporation, Ltd.
1930-1932 Lecturer of Economics at University of California
1931 Becomes President of Silberling Research Corporation, Ltd.
1935 Lecturer in Business Economics at Stanford University
1936-1938 Acting Professor of Business Research at Stanford University
1938-1944 Professor of Business Research at Stanford University
1944 Year of Death
Scope and Content
The collection includes copies of Silberling's reports (1926-1936); copies of his "Confidential Weekly Letters" (1937-1942); "Graphic Surveys of Industry and Finance" (1936-1942); and "Corporation Analyses" of leading corporations (1919-1933). Also included is a short report written by Silberling in 1938 on economic developments in the United states from 1927 to 1938.
Provenance
Gift of Norman J. Silberling to the Jackson Library of Business, 1945. Transferred to Special Collections in 1979.
Access Restrictions
None.
Silberling Research Corporation, Ltd.; Silberling, Norman J., 1892-1944; Economic forecasting--United States.; Reports.; United States--Economic conditions--20th century
- Folder containing The Record of Silberling Forecasts and Investment Policy Since 1927," (until 1937) written by Norman J. Silberling himself. (Othertype 1)
- Bound Silberling Reports #1-#87, 1926 May - 1928 Dec. (Othertype 2)
- Bound Silberling Reports #88-#133, 1929 Jan. - Dec. (Othertype 3)
- Bound Silberling Reports #134-#185, 1930 Jan. - Dec. (Othertype 4)
- Bound Silberling Reports #186-#237, 1931 Jan. - Dec. (Othertype 5)
- Silberling Reports #238-#315, 1932 Jan. - 1933 June; In looseleaf notebook (Othertype 6)
- Silberling Reports, 1933 - 1936 June; In looseleaf notebook (Othertype 7)
  - #337, 11/25/1933
  - #339, 12/9/1933
  - #346, 1/27/1934
  - #351, 3/3/1934
  - #355, 3/31/1934
  - #356, 4/7/1934
  - #364, 6/2/1934
  - #368, 6/30/1934
  - #369, 2/7/1934
  - #373, -#444, 1/5/1935 1/11/1936
- Confidential Weekly Letters, 1937 Sept. - 1938 Dec.; In looseleaf notebook (Othertype 8)
- Confidential Weekly Letters, 1941; In looseleaf notebook (Othertype 9)
- Confidential Weekly Letters, 1942; In looseleaf notebook (Othertype 10)
- Graphic surveys of Industry and Finance, #1-#23, (5/23/1936 - 1/23/1942); In looseleaf notebook (Othertype 11)
- Silberling Research Corporation, Ltd. Corporation Analyses, earning charts on 100 leading companies, 1919-1933 (Othertype 12)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes listing of the 100 companies (both list and charts in alphabetical order) and full explanation of the charts and the resulting analysis.
- Silberling Research Corporation, Ltd. Corporation Analyses, "Comparison of Gross Earnings (of leading companies) with External Business Factors" (Othertype 13)
  Includes about 50 corporations, in alphabetical order.